NIHAL ANAND

Front-end Web Developer
<u>LinkedIn | GitHub | Twitter | Nihal.io</u>

CONTACT

nihalanand@gmail.com 647-330-1841

TECH SKILLS

- React & jQuery
- JavaScript ES6+
- HTML5, CSS3, Sass
- Bootstrap
- RESTful APIs
- Firebase
- Git and GitHub
- C, Python & SQL
- Responsive design
- Team-based and paired programming
- Project scope management
- Adobe Photoshop and Premiere Pro

SOFT SKILLS

- Skillful communicator
- Exceptional listener
- Persuasive and tactful
- Inquisitive and analytical
- Complex problem solver
- Excellent team-player
- Natural leader and motivator
- Self-driven and independent
- Flexible and adaptable
- Receptive and open to all perspectives

HONORS & AWARDS

Canadian House of Commons Certificate of Appreciation (2016)

Recognizing work as Cinematographer on documentary 'Maple Morning' and contribution to Canadian cinema.

I create responsive, accessible and visually cohesive web applications utilizing advanced front-end skills and strong programming fundamentals. My ability to communicate effectively allows me to help others bring their creative vision to life. In nearly a decade as a videographer, I have built expertise in holistically understanding any project brief before meticulously completing all the tasks required.

PROJECTS

Keanu and Who? Live | GitHub

- Search for any two actors to check if they have ever acted together
- Used React and TMDB API to compare movie credits of both actors.

Let's Get Cooking! Live | GitHub

- Search for recipes using ingredients that you have in your pantry
- Used jQuery and AJAX to get data from the Spoonacular API.

The Film Factory Live | CitHub

- Search for an English film to see foreign-language recommendations
- Used data from TMDB API and processed results using React hooks.

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology

2020 - 2021 | Front-End Web Development

- Web Development Immersive Bootcamp
- Accelerated JavaScript (jQuery)
- Intro to Web Dev

University of Toronto, School of Continuing Studies

2015 - 2016 | Post-Graduate Certificate

- Digital Marketing Management

University of Toronto, St. George

2008 - 2013 | Honours Bachelor's of Arts

- English, Media Studies & Cinema Studies

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

Canada One Auto Group (Toronto)

2019 - 2020 | MARKETING VIDEOGRAPHER

Produced visual marketing content adhering to strict visual guidelines while adapting to ever-changing daily targets to guarantee successful business operations of the dealerships.

Vistek (Toronto / Mississauga)

2018 - 2019 | VIDEO SALES CONSULTANT

Exceeded sales targets by advising on the latest video production and photography gear for new and existing clients by getting a complete understanding of their production needs.